<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Srivatsan Sudhir</title>
    <link>srivatsansudhir.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Srivatsan Sudhir</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:12:14 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="srivatsansudhir.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction</title>
      <link>srivatsansudhir.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:12:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>srivatsansudhir.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Greetings, my name is Srivatsan Sudhir. I’m 16 years old and in 11th grade. I’m currently studying in Inventure Academy in Bangalore, India. I enjoy playing chess, watching films and tv shows, and reading. I currently have an FIDE rating of 1030 in chess and have also written multiple articles and short stories for my school newspaper. I also self-published a novel in 2020.
I decided to start writing this blog because I quite enjoy writing, and wanted a platform to put out my thoughts on things that I don’t always have a chance to, while also furthering and honing my writing skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Really Deserves the Spotlight?</title>
      <link>srivatsansudhir.com/posts/my-2nd-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>srivatsansudhir.com/posts/my-2nd-post/</guid>
      <description>Lately, people have been becoming more and more invested and consumed in what goes on both in the continuity and canon of fictional worlds and universes, such as the MCU or Harry Potter, and the minute details of the lives of the world’s biggest celebrities. Unfortunately, this also means that people have become more disillusioned to the real world around them, which reflects in the attention and payroll given to essential workers, such as teachers and doctors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
